<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title><![CDATA[Practical Acts]]></title>
        <description><![CDATA[Practical Acts]]></description>
        <link>http://www.practicalacts.org/</link>
        <generator>The Grid</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 21 Feb 2017 13:56:03 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="http://www.practicalacts.org/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
        <pubDate>Tue, 21 Feb 2017 13:55:14 GMT</pubDate>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Breaking the Equilibrium]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Breaking the Equilibrium</h1>,<img src="https://the-grid-user-content.s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/a93d0482-5985-4c0f-ba88-5337a212afb1.jpg">,<p>I've just finished reading "<a href="http://www.goodreads.com/book/show/24694071-getting-beyond-better">Getting Beyond Better... how Social Entrepreneurship works</a>" by Roger L. Martin and Sally R. Osberg. It's a great read and an important one whether you're a social entrepreneur or in "normal" business.</p>,<p>One section in the introduction really resonated with me and I thought worth sharing here as its relevance to our today is beyond the Social Entrepreneurship topic. It's about Equilibriums... and how to break them:</p>,<blockquote>...the concept of equilibrium change looms large in our thinking. An equilibrium is a balanced, stable system. Left alone, a system in equilibrium will persist in its current state, according to its current structure. The system may well be corrupt, or evil, or unfair, but its forces are in balance and will remain so without intentional action to shift it (and sometimes it will remain even in the face of such action). A system of action can and often will produce a relatively stable equilibrium that is unpleasant and unproductive for some of these actors, typically for the most underprivileged and marginalised.</blockquote>,<p>Unlike the equilibrium of the glass and pivot in the picture most human and societal equilibriums are really tough to break. This is true within organisations undergoing a transformation from the equilibrium of "this is the way things are done around here" and in society at large.</p>,<p>Transformation is hard... but the eventual outcomes are worth every effort as the authours show through great case studies.&nbsp;</p>,<p>The final chapter of the book talks of Paths to Transformation which really resonate if you've tried to do anything the "right" way:</p>,<ul><li>Step1: Understanding the World - developing a real commitment to understanding a particular status quo, how it came to be, and the forces that hold it in place.</li><li>Step2: Envisioning a new future - developing a clear and defined idea of what we seek to achieve: a future resulting from equilibrium change rather than one that preserves the current state.</li><li>Step3: Building a model for change - through creativity and hard-nosed shrewdness!</li><li>Step4: Scaling the solution - scale measured not by an organisation's size or budget but by the effectiveness of that organisation at shifting the equilibrium it targets.&nbsp;</li></ul>,<p>This final step is perhaps the most intriguing when we compare social entrepreneurship to other, more traditional forms of business. It's a step which has encouraged me to put this commentary out. It's a step that suggests that it is only by working together, being transparent and open with others about our methods, can we really scale.</p>,<p>The final paragraph of the book reads:</p>,<blockquote>With the drivers of change - and a four stage model of achieving it - better understood, our hope is that more social entrepreneurs will find their way forward more quickly and effectively, with more funders and supporters stepping up to help them achieve sustainable change. As more social entrepreneurs succeed in transforming injustice and righting the world, we all stand to benefit. Yes, the world can get beyond better - and social entrepreneurs prove it&apos;s possible.</blockquote>,<p>But why do we need to distinguish social entrepreneurship from other, more traditional, forms of business? Businesses and organisations that have inspired me over the years don't need to distinguish between social entrepreneurship and traditional entrepreneurship. They have taken some of these ideas presented in <a href="http://www.goodreads.com/book/show/24694071-getting-beyond-better">Getting Beyond Better&nbsp;</a>and tried to be a force for good.&nbsp;</p>,<p><strong>I hope many more organisations take up the challenge of breaking equilibriums.</strong></p>]]></description>
            <link>http://www.practicalacts.org/breaking-the-equilibrium/index.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">678b7074-fb62-47dd-bbcc-66884d30896e</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 18 Jan 2017 22:41:33 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Design Thinking]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Design Thinking</h1>,<p>I’ve had the opportunity over the last year to study Design Thinking more formally and leveraged some wonderful courses through IdeoU (<a href="http://www.ideou.com/products/leading-for-creativity" title="">Leading for Creativity</a>) and LinkedIn learning (<a href="http:// https//www.linkedin.com/learning/design-thinking-lead-change-in-your-organization" title="">Design Thinking: Lead Change in Your Organisation</a> by Frog; <a href="http:// https//www.linkedin.com/learning/nathan-shedroff-on-design-strategy-and-the-merging-of-business-and-design/design-research-and-dealing-with-ambiguity" title="">Nathan Shedroff on Design Strategy and the Merging of Business and Design</a> by Lynda.com).</p>,<p>It’s stuck me how important building and leveraging design thinking is in today's ever changing world. The core of the learning for me was on how much there is a process to creativity and that there is hope, even for a engineer like me, for us all to become more creative in our workplaces.</p>,<p>There’s a great article on <a href="https://hbr.org/2017/01/use-design-thinking-to-build-commitment-to-a-new-idea?referral=00208&amp;cm_mmc=email-_-newsletter-_-technology-_-technology_date&amp;utm_source=newsletter_technology&amp;utm_medium=email&amp;utm_campaign=technology_date&amp;spMailingID=16422776&amp;spUserID=NDA2MDA2NDg5NDUS1&amp;spJobID=942164574&amp;spReportId=OTQyMTY0NTc0S0" title="">Design Thinking available on HBR</a> right now and do check out the courses I’ve linked above. <strong>The time invested is worth it.</strong></p>,<article><img src="https://s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/the-grid-img/p/2eeaec46985d8d4b915235e7107e30533e0109c3.jpg"><h1>Use Design Thinking to Build Commitment to a New Idea</h1><p>The logic we use to understand the world as it is can hinder us when we seek to understand the world as it could be. Anyone who comes up with new ideas for a living will recognize the challenges this truism presents.</p></article>]]></description>
            <link>http://www.practicalacts.org/design-thinking/index.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">9f365c09-5510-4b7f-9159-3ef9f0054790</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 03 Feb 2017 18:57:45 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The Fourth Industrial Revolution]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>The Fourth Industrial Revolution</h1>,<img src="https://the-grid-user-content.s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/9388a2cd-6360-4568-9356-a5801c47f31f.jpg">,<h2>What it means, how to respond, from the WEF</h2>,<blockquote>We stand on the brink of a technological revolution that will fundamentally alter the way we live, work, and relate to one another. In its scale, scope, and complexity, the transformation will be unlike anything humankind has experienced before. We do not yet know just how it will unfold, but one thing is clear: the response to it must be integrated and comprehensive, involving all stakeholders of the global polity, from the public and private sectors to academia and civil society.</blockquote>,<p>The First Industrial Revolution used water and steam power to mechanize production. The Second used electric power to create mass production. The Third used electronics and information technology to automate production. Now a Fourth Industrial Revolution is building on the Third, the digital revolution that has been occurring since the middle of the last century. It is characterized by a fusion of technologies that is blurring the lines between the physical, digital, and biological spheres.</p>,<iframe src="https://cdn.embedly.com/widgets/media.html?src=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.youtube.com%2Fembed%2FkhjY5LWF3tg%3Ffeature%3Doembed&url=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.youtube.com%2Fwatch%3Fv%3DkhjY5LWF3tg&image=https%3A%2F%2Fi.ytimg.com%2Fvi%2FkhjY5LWF3tg%2Fhqdefault.jpg&key=b7d04c9b404c499eba89ee7072e1c4f7&type=text%2Fhtml&schema=youtube" width="640" height="360" scrolling="no" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe>,<p>There are three reasons why today’s transformations represent not merely a prolongation of the Third Industrial Revolution but rather the arrival of a Fourth and distinct one:</p>,<ul><li>velocity,</li><li>scope, and</li><li>systems impact.</li></ul>,<p><strong>The speed of current breakthroughs has no historical precedent. </strong>When compared with previous industrial revolutions, the Fourth is evolving at an exponential rather than a linear pace. Moreover, it is disrupting almost every industry in every country. And the breadth and depth of these changes herald the transformation of entire systems of production, management, and governance.</p>]]></description>
            <link>http://www.practicalacts.org/the-fourth-industrial-revolution/index.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">6e0c4a0e-cd07-4c16-ba3d-58abdf4a629b</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 25 Jan 2017 21:10:18 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Grit and Resilience]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Grit and Resilience</h1>,<img src="https://the-grid-user-content.s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/ed3b7d1d-cc70-42c7-8c76-e509f58cbd29.jpg">,<p>We all experience adversity and the need for change throughout our lives. Some days everything seems against us, other days maybe a few things disrupt our flow, rare days are those when everything we try works out.</p>,<p>To get through adverse situations, to make change transformational, we must <a href="https://youtu.be/H14bBuluwB8">show grit</a>, be <strong><a href="http://blog.iqmatrix.com/never-give-up">resilient</a></strong>, and <strong><a href="http://blog.strava.com/strive/">strive</a></strong> to succeed. The definition of grit when used in this context is:</p>,<blockquote>Courage and resolve; strength of character</blockquote>]]></description>
            <link>http://www.practicalacts.org/grit-and-resilience/index.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">08fe2185-15ef-473d-9543-4af93a01b27f</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 18 Jan 2017 22:41:33 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Moral Compass]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Moral Compass</h1>,<img src="https://the-grid-user-content.s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/59890dd2-409b-4c1b-bf78-153a6eba69e4.jpg">,<p>There’s a lot of talk and things written about the rights and wrongs of our world at the moment. No one can stand by an argument saying everything is going swimmingly but its the tone of the arguments I am most confused by. We seem to have left logic and reason behind and in some areas are rewarding aggressive behaviour and soundbites. Behind this I think we’ve, again, lost something of our morals.</p>,<p>I started to really think about this after I left Wood Mackenzie. When I left there was a leaving card, a few drinks, and a goodbye speech. It was all rather humbling and during all of this someone said to me they were losing a Moral Compass. I remember feeling very touched and a little embarrassed at that point. The evening moved on with a few more drinks and silliness but something kept niggling me about the term.</p>]]></description>
            <link>http://www.practicalacts.org/moral-compass/index.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">81d76c10-1dd4-48fc-9de4-9d9dcb1a9f03</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 18 Jan 2017 22:41:33 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Competing in a world with big data]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Competing in a world with big data</h1>,<img src="https://imgflo.herokuapp.com/graph/2b2431f8e7ba7b0/b483f34be191b30cb438f8e6b8e037be/croprotate.png?cropheight=400&cropwidth=512&degrees=0&input=https%3A%2F%2Fthe-grid-user-content.s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com%2Fad43fdc2-07a9-4de8-a294-b0e4605acbd8.png&x=96&y=0">,<p>I'm excited to have been at Harvard Business School in June 2016 participating in a course on <strong><a href="http://www.exed.hbs.edu/programs/data/Pages/default.aspx">Competing on Business Analytics and Big Data</a></strong>. The premise of the program is:</p>,<blockquote>As digital technologies continue to transform the marketplace, companies across the globe are collecting an enormous amount of data. Unfortunately, many of these same businesses lack the talent and structure to turn big data into a competitive advantage.</blockquote>,<p>The first question I have is how do businesses currently think of this? Is big data an opportunity or a curse? I'm on the side of the opportunity and a <a href="https://twitter.com/PracticalActs/status/730599085900767232">twitter poll agreed</a>. However, it’s worth considering as there are countless examples of where reading data wrongly has driven the wrong decisions. </p>]]></description>
            <link>http://www.practicalacts.org/competing-in-a-world-with-big-data/index.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">e92d4bf2-f5c6-4a55-ac43-d1fd4b6cb159</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 18 Jan 2017 22:41:33 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Digital Transformation and the importance of iteration]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Digital Transformation and the importance of iteration</h1>,<img src="https://the-grid-user-content.s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/ec1d806a-db0b-48b0-b1c3-70b26efca0d5.png">,<p>Reading the press, reviewing social media, and even in work presentations, it is easy to think that there is no continuum between incredible success and downright failure. Our pictures can be airbrushed, “facts” are single sourced to use on one side of the argument, snap polls are treated as gospel, and the distance between jealousy and ridicule too close.</p>,<p>But what has all of that got to do with Digital Transformation? Digital seems to be the great promise of the moment for so many businesses and organisations as they look for opportunities to grow. But too often Digital programs seem to jump to an end game before any transformation has happened. A significant program is designed and an end to end project plan put into action. For a tiny percentile it all works out and the beauty of a solution shines through. But for most more money is spent, teams are disrupted, results are not achieved and disillusionment sets in. Promise to failure and nothing in between.</p>]]></description>
            <link>http://www.practicalacts.org/digital-transformation-and-the-importance-of-iteration/index.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">a71b0e3d-ea04-4ad1-9a98-9539c3696032</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 18 Jan 2017 22:41:34 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[8 ideas for customer centric transformation]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>8 ideas for customer centric transformation</h1>,<img src="https://the-grid-user-content.s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/0e13cb7b-b7c2-4551-a311-d32598e1ab5a.png">,<p>In Sept 2015 I spent a bunch of time reflecting on Wood Mackenzie's customer led transformation and then presenting at Dreamforce15 (<a href="https://www.slideshare.net/secret/hxyLsokHHZCSgL">slides here</a>) on what it takes to transform. I posted on Twitter a short comment on eight key thoughts. Here's the summary of them:</p>]]></description>
            <link>http://www.practicalacts.org/8-ideas-for-customer-centric-transformation/index.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">85ac6c84-8f3e-416c-92e7-4048b1fca387</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 18 Jan 2017 22:41:34 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Thinking, Tinkering, Leading Transformation]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Thinking, Tinkering, Leading Transformation</h1>,<img src="https://the-grid-user-content.s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/02cd2563-a198-4d8d-a414-bc07516a1a0b.jpg">,<p>Why Thinking, Tinkering, Leading Transformation as a heading? Coming from a fascination with the opportunity we have in todays global and digital world. Matched with the challenges people and organisations face to be transformational, sustainable, and to focus on doing the right thing.</p>]]></description>
            <link>http://www.practicalacts.org/thinking-tinkering-leading-transformation/index.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">81890726-b5f3-40fd-9b9b-ab997cc43092</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 18 Jan 2017 22:41:34 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[#Pledge for Parity]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>#Pledge for Parity</h1>,<img src="https://the-grid-user-content.s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/ca64e380-a96c-416e-aeeb-a71c681d697c.jpg" alt="Pledge for Parity. Start making pledges to drive real change and ensure we are creating a level playing field for talent to grow and thrive.">,<p>I'm proud to have been part of the team that helped Wood Mackenzie start making pledges to drive real change and ensure we are creating a level playing field for talent to grow and thrive.</p>,<p>We've come up with some key areas for us to work on and are building energy internally and externally around these 14 pledges (<a href="https://www.linkedin.com/pulse/pledgeforparity-stuart-mills?trk=mp-author-card">originally published in March 2016</a>):</p>]]></description>
            <link>http://www.practicalacts.org/pledge-for-parity/index.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">950bdd52-a02a-4485-9ff2-93c94395b3fa</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 18 Jan 2017 22:41:33 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>