<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title><![CDATA[Practical Acts]]></title>
        <description><![CDATA[Practical Acts]]></description>
        <link>http://www.practicalacts.org/</link>
        <generator>The Grid</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Thu, 19 Jan 2017 15:37:18 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="http://www.practicalacts.org/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
        <pubDate>Thu, 19 Jan 2017 15:37:14 GMT</pubDate>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Breaking the Equilibrium]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Breaking the Equilibrium</h1>,<img src="https://the-grid-user-content.s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/a93d0482-5985-4c0f-ba88-5337a212afb1.jpg">,<p>I've just started reading "<a href="http://www.goodreads.com/book/show/24694071-getting-beyond-better">Getting Beyond Better... how Social Entrepreneurship works</a>" by Roger L. Martin and Sally R. Osberg. A few chapters in and its a great read.</p>,<p>One section in the introduction really resonated with me and I thought worth sharing here as its relevance to our today is beyond the Social Entrepreneurship topic. It's about Equilibriums... and how to break them:</p>]]></description>
            <link>http://www.practicalacts.org/breaking-the-equilibrium/index.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">678b7074-fb62-47dd-bbcc-66884d30896e</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 18 Jan 2017 22:41:33 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Grit and Resilience]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Grit and Resilience</h1>,<img src="https://the-grid-user-content.s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/ed3b7d1d-cc70-42c7-8c76-e509f58cbd29.jpg">,<p>We all experience adversity and the need for change throughout our lives. Some days everything seems against us, other days maybe a few things disrupt our flow, rare days are those when everything we try works out.</p>,<p>To get through adverse situations, to make change transformational, we must <a href="https://youtu.be/H14bBuluwB8">show grit</a>, be <strong><a href="http://blog.iqmatrix.com/never-give-up">resilient</a></strong>, and <strong><a href="http://blog.strava.com/strive/">strive</a></strong> to succeed. The definition of grit when used in this context is:</p>,<blockquote>Courage and resolve; strength of character</blockquote>]]></description>
            <link>http://www.practicalacts.org/grit-and-resilience/index.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">08fe2185-15ef-473d-9543-4af93a01b27f</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 18 Jan 2017 22:41:33 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Moral Compass]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Moral Compass</h1>,<img src="https://the-grid-user-content.s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/59890dd2-409b-4c1b-bf78-153a6eba69e4.jpg">,<p>There’s a lot of talk and things written about the rights and wrongs of our world at the moment. No one can stand by an argument saying everything is going swimmingly but its the tone of the arguments I am most confused by. We seem to have left logic and reason behind and in some areas are rewarding aggressive behaviour and soundbites. Behind this I think we’ve, again, lost something of our morals.</p>,<p>I started to really think about this after I left Wood Mackenzie. When I left there was a leaving card, a few drinks, and a goodbye speech. It was all rather humbling and during all of this someone said to me they were losing a Moral Compass. I remember feeling very touched and a little embarrassed at that point. The evening moved on with a few more drinks and silliness but something kept niggling me about the term.</p>,<p>With summer upon us and inspired by Stephan Sagmeister’s TED talk <a href="http://www.ted.com/talks/stefan_sagmeister_the_power_of_time_off?language=en">“The power of time off”</a>, we decided to take a break and travel for two months with our young children. The time out was refreshing and reflective. We left the UK just after the divisive Brexit vote and saw some of the Clinton/Trump division in the USA before heading to Costa Rica and seeing this incredible country with an environment and society that’s flourishing and is happy. Along the way I read a few books including a great one by Kenan Malik – “The Quest for a Moral Compass”. There are lots of wonderful quotes from the book but one that stood out is in Chapter 11, The human triumph, and reads:</p>,<blockquote>The very idea of morality relies on viewing humans not as machines but as conscious agents capable of making choices and taking responsibility for their actions.</blockquote>,<p>Coming back to the UK and a search for new opportunities I’m convinced that we’ve lost a requirement of ourselves and our leaders to have a Moral Compass especially in times of dramatic change. Our Moral Compass is critical to us making good choices and decisions.</p>,<p>The Cambridge Dictionary definition of a Moral Compass is:</p>,<blockquote>A natural feeling that makes people know what is right and wrong and how they should behave.</blockquote>,<p>But reflecting on this, and working through Malik’s book, I’m convinced this compass is anything but a “natural feeling” and we must not leave to chance the development of a Moral Compass in our children, our leaders, and ourselves.</p>,<p>I’ve led and been part of a number of transformational change programs in my life and keeping my moral compass level and pointing north has always depended on learning from others. On reaching out to leaders I respect, mentors and mentees, and colleagues. It’s also required me to reach inside myself and hold myself to learned standards of behaviour.</p>,<p>If you think about growing up I’ll bet you can conjure up memories of how you learnt right from wrong and who helped you? Can you reach out to them, say thank you, ask them to keep doing more, and challenge yourself to help too? </p>,<p>To be a little topical again. Brexit is Brexit and the US Presidential race was a farce. <strong>The optimist in me believes there is always time to ask that our leaders, regardless of mistakes made in their past, pull out their moral compass, dust it off, get help in improving it, and lead us well. </strong>Please expect this of them as you work, vote, and lobby.</p>]]></description>
            <link>http://www.practicalacts.org/moral-compass/index.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">81d76c10-1dd4-48fc-9de4-9d9dcb1a9f03</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 18 Jan 2017 22:41:33 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Competing in a world with big data]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Competing in a world with big data</h1>,<img src="https://the-grid-user-content.s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/ad43fdc2-07a9-4de8-a294-b0e4605acbd8.png">,<p>I'm excited to have been at Harvard Business School in June 2016 participating in a course on <strong><a href="http://www.exed.hbs.edu/programs/data/Pages/default.aspx">Competing on Business Analytics and Big Data</a></strong>. The premise of the program is:</p>,<blockquote>As digital technologies continue to transform the marketplace, companies across the globe are collecting an enormous amount of data. Unfortunately, many of these same businesses lack the talent and structure to turn big data into a competitive advantage.</blockquote>,<p>The first question I have is how do businesses currently think of this? Is big data an opportunity or a curse? I'm on the side of the opportunity and a <a href="https://twitter.com/PracticalActs/status/730599085900767232">twitter poll agreed</a>. However, it’s worth considering as there are countless examples of where reading data wrongly has driven the wrong decisions. As the volumes of data increase and as leaders we get further from the raw data, how do we trust the insight? As a <a href="https://www.dataloft.co.uk/lies-damned-lies-statistics-2/">blog post </a>from Dataloft says:</p>,<blockquote>Yet, when there are sometimes conflicting views from different sources reporting on the same subject, how do we know which one to believe? ... It&rsquo;s why big data is both a blessing and a curse. The capacity to manage and crunch enormous data sets creates incredible opportunities for new insights ... but the daily bombardment of new and often contradictory statistics, can be utterly bewildering.</blockquote>,<p>Getting answers to good questions is a way to think of getting value from business analytics and big data. As Julian Birkinshaw, Strategy Professor at London Business School, says in his article on <a href="https://www.london.edu/faculty-and-research/lbsr/diie-nov-drowning-in-numbers#.V3LYjFfnXw5">Drowning in numbers</a>:</p>,<blockquote>Big data is everywhere, promising better and faster decision-making. But more information doesn&rsquo;t necessarily yield better solutions. Computers are good at providing answers, but they are hopeless at knowing what questions to ask.</blockquote>,<p>We're also challenged by Ronald van Loon in <a href="http://www.cio.com/article/3050832/business-intelligence/big-data-and-machine-learning-is-the-glass-half-empty.html">an article </a>to think about if some skepticism on big data and machine learning is …. glass half empty?</p>,<blockquote>The reality is that technology is shifting faster than leadership can understand what threats it poses. Large bureaucratic companies that simply adopt the big data paradigm will struggle to keep up with explosion of unstructured data and data streams that has caused the role and value of information to drastically change.</blockquote>,<p>We, of course, need to think positively about the opportunity and there are a building list of great examples of where real value is being generated. For example, <a href="http://www.digitalistmag.com/future-of-work/2016/04/22/big-data-integral-part-of-talent-recruiting-04163940">Evan Sinar writes</a> that big data is now an integral part of talent recruiting. Perhaps the way to think of these opportunities is as McKinsey’s Nimal Manuel and Shilpa Aggarwal <a href="https://medium.com/world-economic-forum/big-data-should-be-driven-by-business-needs-not-technology-78ece2eca9b#.h1egbal8a">wrote for the World Economic Forum</a>:</p>,<blockquote>Regardless of how it&rsquo;s practised in many companies, big data analytics is not trawl fishing: it&rsquo;s spear fishing.</blockquote>,<p>So here's the next question I have. How ready is your organisation to take this opportunity? I'd like to bet most organisations are just getting started.for example, only 20% of participants in <a href="http://www.engineering.com/AdvancedManufacturing/ArticleID/12069/How-Can-Big-Data-Enhance-Quality-in-Manufacturing.aspx#.VzT_K0gGGHg.twitter">a study</a> by the American Society for Quality (ASQ) believe their organisation is using BigData to gain competitive advantage.I'm hoping this Harvard course and discussions with participants will help me turn business analytics and big data to opportunity by considering these topics:</p>,<ul><li>Competing on business analytics to build customer trust and generate more data</li></ul>,<ul><li>Recognising and exploiting the difference between correlational and causal patterns</li></ul>,<ul><li>Exploring the data explosion in the "four Vs"—variety, velocity, voracity, and volume</li></ul>,<ul><li>Applying experimentation and data analysis to build breakthrough business models</li></ul>,<ul><li>Improving company's analytics capabilities to create and capture more value</li></ul>,<ul><li>Managing company with real-time analytics to improve overall efficiency</li></ul>,<ul><li>Comparing big-data analytics with a traditional small-data approach</li></ul>,<ul><li>Understanding the strategic implications of supply chain and marketing analytics</li></ul>,<ul><li>Attracting and developing data analytics teams to build and hold a competitive edge</li></ul>,<ul><li>Using data analytics to create smart, connected products that reshape your company and industry</li></ul>,<p><em><strong>Good luck with your journey to leveraging business analytics and big data.</strong></em></p>,<img src="https://the-grid-user-content.s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/437342cc-b34a-42d4-810b-33752dae7473.png">]]></description>
            <link>http://www.practicalacts.org/competing-in-a-world-with-big-data/index.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">e92d4bf2-f5c6-4a55-ac43-d1fd4b6cb159</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 18 Jan 2017 22:41:33 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Digital Transformation and the importance of iteration]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Digital Transformation and the importance of iteration</h1>,<img src="https://the-grid-user-content.s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/ec1d806a-db0b-48b0-b1c3-70b26efca0d5.png">,<p>Reading the press, reviewing social media, and even in work presentations, it is easy to think that there is no continuum between incredible success and downright failure. Our pictures can be airbrushed, “facts” are single sourced to use on one side of the argument, snap polls are treated as gospel, and the distance between jealousy and ridicule too close.</p>,<p>But what has all of that got to do with Digital Transformation? Digital seems to be the great promise of the moment for so many businesses and organisations as they look for opportunities to grow. But too often Digital programs seem to jump to an end game before any transformation has happened. A significant program is designed and an end to end project plan put into action. For a tiny percentile it all works out and the beauty of a solution shines through. But for most more money is spent, teams are disrupted, results are not achieved and disillusionment sets in. Promise to failure and nothing in between. </p>,<p>It has always been true that a plan is only good for a minute after completing it but with the speed of digital development its never been more important to plan to iterate the plan. In funding digital initiatives don’t get a spending plan that only covers the known plan. This is not about contingency funds… this is real follow on money that will be needed, not just if things go “wrong”. I’ve always liked to think of planning and funding digital just like VCs do a start up. Plan to seed, plan to pivot, plan to secure second and third round funding etc, etc.</p>,<p>Cloud based technologies are a great example now where delivering the value promised requires an agile approach. Build and commit to a huge vision but spend on it and deliver it incrementally and you can be successful. Leverage ideas such as marginal gains and black box thinking around failure to keep reviewing programs. Cloud based technologies are designed to be constantly developed, leveraging that aspect about them is as key as choosing the right platform for your needs today.</p>,<p>A key element to digital is checking the landscape hasn’t completely changed, of course, so it's critical a to have a regular blue sky review. Using design thinking, rituals, and agile development help guard against “climbing the wrong mountain” as well as making incremental steps.</p>,<p>Turning this article around at bit. I hope this gives some confidence that embarking on digital transformation doesn't need us to know all the answers before we start developments. You’ve got to plan to fail, plan to learn, and then - after a good few rounds - to then succeed. And critically you've got to build a culture where people are confident enough to try and fail and try again. Then your digital transformation can succeed.</p>,<p><em>If you’d like to discuss this note please get in touch. I’m happy to share some real life, occasionally bitter, experiences that I’ve learned from.</em></p>]]></description>
            <link>http://www.practicalacts.org/digital-transformation-and-the-importance-of-iteration/index.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">a71b0e3d-ea04-4ad1-9a98-9539c3696032</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 18 Jan 2017 22:41:34 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[8 ideas for customer centric transformation]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>8 ideas for customer centric transformation</h1>,<img src="https://the-grid-user-content.s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/a2f061f7-091e-415e-8793-84aebc169fc8.png">,<p>In Sept 2015 I spent a bunch of time reflecting on Wood Mackenzie's customer led transformation and then presenting at Dreamforce15 (<a href="https://www.slideshare.net/secret/hxyLsokHHZCSgL">slides here</a>) on what it takes to transform. I posted on Twitter a short comment on eight key thoughts. Here's the summary of them:</p>,<ul><li><a href="https://twitter.com/PracticalActs/status/643412677096800256">Transformation starts with </a><strong><a href="https://twitter.com/PracticalActs/status/643412677096800256">clear ambition</a></strong><a href="https://twitter.com/PracticalActs/status/643412677096800256"> and a brave review of what really matters. Sustainable growth through client led innovation is a good place to start!</a></li></ul>,<ul><li><a href="https://twitter.com/PracticalActs/status/643516123602911233">Transformation needs organisations to </a><strong><a href="https://twitter.com/PracticalActs/status/643516123602911233">focus on clients</a></strong><a href="https://twitter.com/PracticalActs/status/643516123602911233">. Customers are the life blood of any organization, listen to them!</a></li></ul>,<ul><li><a href="https://twitter.com/PracticalActs/status/643674408666710016">Transformation must paint a </a><strong><a href="https://twitter.com/PracticalActs/status/643674408666710016">blueprint &amp; a roadmap</a></strong><a href="https://twitter.com/PracticalActs/status/643674408666710016">. It must be engaging customers, employees, stakeholders!</a></li></ul>,<ul><li><a href="https://twitter.com/PracticalActs/status/643775031500255232">Transformation needs you to </a><strong><a href="https://twitter.com/PracticalActs/status/643775031500255232">engage your people</a></strong><a href="https://twitter.com/PracticalActs/status/643775031500255232">. They will lead if given the chance!</a></li></ul>,<ul><li><a href="https://twitter.com/PracticalActs/status/643878498071801859">Transformation is tough. </a><strong><a href="https://twitter.com/PracticalActs/status/643878498071801859">Manage the journey.</a></strong><a href="https://twitter.com/PracticalActs/status/643878498071801859"> Expect the unexpected, plan for it, take it in your stride!</a></li></ul>,<ul><li><a href="https://twitter.com/PracticalActs/status/643803547801387008">Transformation is faster if you </a><strong><a href="https://twitter.com/PracticalActs/status/643803547801387008">integrate client processes</a></strong><a href="https://twitter.com/PracticalActs/status/643803547801387008">. Bring customer led insight to the heart of everyday, make it relevant for all!</a></li></ul>,<ul><li><a href="https://twitter.com/PracticalActs/status/644137469445820416">Transformation doesn't happen behind a desk. </a><strong><a href="https://twitter.com/PracticalActs/status/644137469445820416">Enable access when &amp; where needed</a></strong><a href="https://twitter.com/PracticalActs/status/644137469445820416"> to the key tools and processes. Life is mobile, embrace new innovations that enable it.</a></li></ul>,<ul><li><a href="https://twitter.com/PracticalActs/status/644240849090531328">Transformation, despite grand ambition, is often done </a><strong><a href="https://twitter.com/PracticalActs/status/644240849090531328">one step at a time</a></strong><a href="https://twitter.com/PracticalActs/status/644240849090531328">. Find time. set goals. be practical. act. #domore</a></li></ul>]]></description>
            <link>http://www.practicalacts.org/8-ideas-for-customer-centric-transformation/index.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">85ac6c84-8f3e-416c-92e7-4048b1fca387</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 18 Jan 2017 22:41:34 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Thinking, Tinkering, Leading Transformation]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Thinking, Tinkering, Leading Transformation</h1>,<img src="https://the-grid-user-content.s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/02cd2563-a198-4d8d-a414-bc07516a1a0b.jpg">,<p>Why Thinking, Tinkering, Leading Transformation as a heading? Coming from a fascination with the opportunity we have in todays global and digital world. Matched with the challenges people and organisations face to be transformational, sustainable, and to focus on doing the right thing.</p>,<ul><li><strong>Thinking</strong> because understanding, setting, and communicating vision and goals is a critical part of leading organisations that maximise their impact. Jump straight into doing and a whole lot of wasted effort could occur... if you're climbing the wrong hill. To quote Alvin Toffler: <em>“You’ve got to think about big things while you’re doing small things, so that all the small things go in the right direction.”</em></li></ul>,<ul><li><strong>Tinkering</strong> because reality is never quite as we foresee it. While we all love to think we start with a well defined set of goals and a good plan it is only in our experimentation, failure, iteration, looking for marginal gains, and sometimes wholesale adaptation of the plan along the way that we maximise our impact. As Matthew Syed pitches in his wonderful book, <a href="http://www.matthewsyed.co.uk/books/">Black Box Thinking</a>: <em>"Until we change the way we think about failure, the ambition of high performance will often remain a mirage."</em></li></ul>,<ul><li><strong>Leading Transformation</strong> because maximising performance and impact needs leadership. Leadership that has a good moral compass, leadership that is passionate about the vision and the people involved, leadership that is willing to fail and learn, leadership that embraces change for good. To quote Jack Welch <em>“Good business leaders create a vision, articulate the vision, passionately own the vision, and relentlessly drive it to completion.”</em></li></ul>]]></description>
            <link>http://www.practicalacts.org/thinking-tinkering-leading-transformation/index.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">81890726-b5f3-40fd-9b9b-ab997cc43092</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 18 Jan 2017 22:41:34 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[#Pledge for Parity]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>#Pledge for Parity</h1>,<img src="https://the-grid-user-content.s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/ca64e380-a96c-416e-aeeb-a71c681d697c.jpg" alt="Pledge for Parity. Start making pledges to drive real change and ensure we are creating a level playing field for talent to grow and thrive.">,<p>I'm proud to have been part of the team that helped Wood Mackenzie start making pledges to drive real change and ensure we are creating a level playing field for talent to grow and thrive.</p>,<p>We've come up with some key areas for us to work on and are building energy internally and externally around these 14 pledges (<a href="https://www.linkedin.com/pulse/pledgeforparity-stuart-mills?trk=mp-author-card">originally published in March 2016</a>):</p>,<h2>Build supportive environments and work to eliminate conscious and unconscious bias</h2>,<ul><li>I pledge to become more aware of my own biases and work to eliminate them</li></ul>,<img src="https://the-grid-user-content.s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/dd215de0-7dca-4a22-8dcf-99cd1208273f.png">,<ul><li>I pledge to appropriately challenge unfair behaviour and practices I observe and to not walk on past</li></ul>,<ul><li>I pledge to challenge myself to be gender aware and promote parity</li></ul>,<ul><li>I pledge to seek out perspectives different from my own and encourage everyone to contribute</li></ul>,<h2>Build a stronger pipeline of female talent</h2>,<ul><li>I pledge to offer opportunities for growth to both the men and women in my team</li></ul>,<img src="https://the-grid-user-content.s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/72e841f5-cfa9-42b4-a1bb-272d5b802a31.png">,<ul><li>I pledge to sponsor a woman to help her achieve her career goals</li></ul>,<ul><li>I pledge to enter a mentoring or coaching relationship and educate myself on how this can support gender balance.</li></ul>,<ul><li>I pledge to challenge our leaders to ensure men and women are treated equally in all aspects of our business</li></ul>,<img src="https://the-grid-user-content.s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/91d70c22-c39b-48a2-9abc-1fe9716def9d.png">,<h2>Greater flexibility of roles and working patterns</h2>,<ul><li>I pledge to respect anyone who uses flexible working to attain balance</li></ul>,<ul><li>I pledge to think about how my life - work balance can improve with flexible working</li></ul>,<ul><li>I pledge to help create a culture of flexibility for everyone on my team</li></ul>,<ul><li>I pledge to support colleagues stepping off and back on</li></ul>,<ul><li>I pledge to take co-ownership of my own exit and re-entry plan</li></ul>,<ul><li>I pledge to support and respect the decision to take paternity leave</li></ul>,<blockquote>Lets drive equal opportunity for all so we maximise the potential we have in our world.</blockquote>]]></description>
            <link>http://www.practicalacts.org/pledge-for-parity/index.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">950bdd52-a02a-4485-9ff2-93c94395b3fa</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 18 Jan 2017 22:41:33 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Do More... Through Sport]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Do More... Through Sport</h1>,<img src="https://the-grid-user-content.s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/dae9da35-82de-4167-8c58-d9608925af39.png">,<p>So much of our ability to do more seems to me to stem from the influence of those around us - our communities... be that family, friends, workplace, local community, broader networks, church, political party, country, online, charities, etc..</p>,<p>Today's world is often seen to resolve more and more around individuals, but none of us truly strive without the influence of those around us. It has to be the creation of positive, peaceful communities with open arms on inclusion that the world will become a better place.</p>,<p>Sport to me always creates a positive community even if for the shortest time in cases. Running a marathon (or something a little more manageable!) creates a community of people focused on achieving something amazing for a few hours. It doesn't matter if you win the race as long as you perform to the standard you want to, or even just finish! What does matter is that for a short few hours (using the London Marathon as an example) 35,000 people are focused on the same goal, with their own 2 feet, with millions of supporters, and in this case raising money and profiles of hundreds of charities.</p>,<blockquote>The positive energy, created through serious effort, during a race like this is palatable and with the wonders of internet and television that energy passes along to more and more people.</blockquote>,<p>A running race is one example where many of us can participate but as individuals. Team sports are another week by week activity that millions of us are lucky enough to do. A community develops around a Saturday game beyond the players. Take my old hockey club... our week involved a training session with all the other teams on Wednesday nights... and a few drinks afterwards! Then Saturday morning came and the team of 15 (11+4subs) meets on a cold Astroturf pitch at 9:30am. A short warm up... the opposition team have just arrived having driven an hour to our ground... we say hello and then it's into the business of the game and everyone’s focus turns to performing as well as they can and to win the game. Win or lose the teams shake hands at the end and head to our club bar to reflect on the game and get to know a few new people and sharing the stories of the week with team players.</p>,<blockquote>And that&apos;s just the start of it... then a meal is shared... sandwiches again... then the other club teams start to arrive and before you know it there&apos;s 100 people enjoying a positive day all built around a few games of hockey.</blockquote>,<p>Perhaps the Tour de France and the Olympics are events many of us can only dream of riding or racing in. However, if you've ever been lucky enough to visits these events you'll be buzzing for the rest of your life. The effort put into these events is huge and goes way beyond the athletes that compete; we can each Do More to make sure events like these happen.Take the Olympics as an example. A whole community of people is built in a different city and country every 2years to organise and then run the winter and Summer Olympics. I was lucky enough to attend the Athens and London Olympics... and yes there were some rough edges but that overriding sense of a global community built around a positive thing... sports... was amazing. I will always remember a city full of normal people carrying their country's flag without malice to each other but with faces of awe built around how amazing it is to see the world communities together at peace. Yes there is excellence and that drives excesses but overriding all of this is a sense that if we all put our mind to it and choose to live to the Olympic ideals, rather than criticise others for their lack of doing so, the world can be a better place. The Olympics is but a framework for a proportion of the world to spend some time together on a positive thing. In the end sport is not life or death it's far more important than that! Because it helps us have a framework for community and development that is peaceful.It takes work to live up to ideals. In Built to Last, Porras and Collins, say:</p>,<blockquote>that crossing the boundary of company values is when a company proves those values.</blockquote>,<p>Dealing with drug cheats is one place a sport deals with living up to ideals. But that's more high profile. Each of us can do more to ensure the ideals of fair play and development of a community stay real in each of the sports we do.</p>,<p>So I believe you can do more through doing more sport and doing more to live up to the ideals of the sports you play or support. But you can go even further and support organisations like Right to Play, which is founded on an Olympic ideal and works around the world using a child right to play as a basis for making sure children have the opportunity for play and that they have coaches they can learn from. This charity has such a positive way to interact with some of the poorest communities in the world... doing things like using their red footballs to play soccer... of course... but also to play a game to bring HIV Aids education... they ask the children to play a short game of soccer and then they'll stop for a game of pass the ball behind your back... the coach shouts stop and then asks the children... where's the ball. They don't all know of course... they can't see it... even the child holding the ball may be confused in the excitement... you get the picture... A very serious message delivered in a very powerful, visual way, but in a fun environment, shared with others. Very very powerful.</p>,<blockquote>So do more sport... but think about doing even more through sport.</blockquote>]]></description>
            <link>http://www.practicalacts.org/do-more-through-sport/index.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">45694410-0c6d-4096-910b-c73ebb5430f0</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 18 Jan 2017 22:41:35 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The serious matter of play]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>The serious matter of play</h1>,<img src="https://the-grid-user-content.s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/45909f9a-7064-4dc3-9703-df4e13dbbf19.png">,<p>We tend to think of play as a child's territory but we loose a lot by thinking just that. Play is a part of life that drives innovation, stimulates communities, helps us enjoy life... to name but a few things.</p>,<p>So a question... do you play enough? Like a child plays? With others? To explore and discover? To have fun? To get to know people? To learn a new skill? To test a new idea? To try something... just because?</p>,<p>I'll bet you don't. Why not?</p>,<p><strong>Here's some other reading on this subject...</strong></p>,<p><em>From TED.COM:</em></p>,<p>A pioneer in research on play, <strong><a href="http://www.ted.com/talks/stuart_brown_says_play_is_more_than_fun_it_s_vital?language=en">Dr. Stuart Brown says</a></strong> humor, games, roughhousing, flirtation and fantasy are more than just fun. Plenty of play in childhood makes for happy, smart adults -- and keeping it up can make us smarter at any age.</p>,<p><strong><a href="http://www.ted.com/talks/john_hunter_on_the_world_peace_game">John Hunter puts all the problems of the world on a 4'x5' plywood board </a></strong>-- and lets his 4th-graders solve them. At TED2011, he explains how his World Peace Game engages schoolkids, and why the complex lessons it teaches -- spontaneous, and always surprising -- go further than classroom lectures can.</p>,<p>At TEDxBG in Sofia, <strong><a href="http://www.ted.com/talks/steve_keil_a_manifesto_for_play_for_bulgaria_and_beyond">Steve Keil fights the "serious meme"</a></strong> that has infected his home of Bulgaria -- and calls for a return to play to revitalize the economy, education and society. A sparkling talk with a universal message for people everywhere who are reinventing their workplaces, schools, lives.</p>,<p><em>From a few interesting connections:</em></p>,<p>Kevin Carroll: Finding your own “<strong><a href="http://v4.kevincarrollkatalyst.com/books">red rubber ball</a></strong>” and chasing it to your heart’s content, he argues, is the surest route to peace, prosperity, and happiness</p>,<p><strong><a href="http://www.righttoplay.com/">Right to Play</a></strong>: To improve the lives of children in some of the most disadvantaged areas of the world by using the power of sport and play for development, health and peace.</p>]]></description>
            <link>http://www.practicalacts.org/the-serious-matter-of-play/index.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">5355c9be-63ba-4d5e-848e-7914e93d962e</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 18 Jan 2017 22:41:34 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>